PETER STEVENS

07727 900494 | Peterstevens510@gmail.com | https://github.com/Thatguy560

Profile

I'm a Junior Developer and Makers Academy alumni, striving for a position where I'm constantly learning and developing my skills and knowledge within a continuously evolving industry. After years spent working in the financial sector, I came to the conclusion that this industry would not provide the mental stimulation and opportunities for growth needed to maintain my interest. After conversing with friends working as developers and my own research, I decided to train for a career in software development. I enrolled at Makers because of their great track record and emphasis on practical, real world experience, pair programming and holistic development. This proved an excellent decision as the experience provided me with a comprehensive understanding of the basics of software development. My time spent at Makers furthered my skills with Ruby and Javascript, taught me the importance of effective Github collaboration practices and reinforced my skills with teamwork and problem solving. For a list of all the projects I've worked on, please visit my GitHub linked in the header to see some examples.

Education

Makers Academy 01/2020 - 05/2020

Software Developer Bootcamp, London Liverpool Street

My studies with Makers Academy helped establish the basic skills required for a career in software development. This education has provided a good understanding of the subject and given me the confidence to tackle increasingly complex projects. My current language of choice is Ruby but I also have a working knowledge of Javascript.

BPP 07/2017 – 11/2018

AAT Level 3, London Liverpool Street

Qualified - Pass - 78% Achieved Studied as part of my finance apprenticeship at The Association of Commonwealth Universities.

Chace Community School Sixth 09/2012 - 08/2015

Form A Levels, Enfield

A2 Level: Maths (B), Physics (C), Chemistry (D), AS Level:

Maths (B), Physics (C), Chemistry (C)

Chace Community School 09/2007 – 06/2012

GCSE's. Enfield

9 GCSEs (Including English & Maths) Grades A*- C

References

Ray Green

English Rural, Finance Director, Ray.Green@englishrural.org.uk, 07806 851217 (M)

Khairul Bashar

Association of Commonwealth Universities, Deputy Finance Officer, Khairul.Bashar@acu.ac.uk, 07738 255094 (M)

Employment History

English Rural

03/2019 - 10/2019

Temporary Finance Assistant, Westminster

Some Responsibilities Included: Download and process Rent Receipts, Housing Benefit Schedules, Standing Orders and Cheques, Update Rent Receipt Schedule, Maintain Cashbook and bank reconciliation, Produce Monthly Rent Arrears summary report for Housing Manager's, Update Capital Expenditure spreadsheet, preparation of Annual Service Charge statement, Assist in the maintenance of Fixed Asset Register.

Finance Apprentice

03/2017 - 01/2019

The Association of Commonwealth Universities, Euston

Some Responsibilities Included: Entering purchase invoices, Maintained supplier and customer records, processing credit card statements and posting associated journals, Responding to supplier and scholar queries, Entering international payments, Assisted with company audits, Entering journal information into the Exchequer Finance System.

Trainee Accounts Technician

10/2015 - 10/2016

Xhi Accounting Limited, Caledonian Road

Some Responsibilities Included: Processing HMRC and Companies House requests for client information and authorisation, Produced Sole Trader Accounts, Prepared year end accounts and Journals, performed Bank reconciliations, Bookkeeping & audit accounts, Personal tax calculations, Produced profit and loss reports.

Skills

Languages & Frameworks

Ruby, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Rails, React, jQuery, Sinatra, Bootstrap, PostgreSQL

Practices

Object Oriented Programming, TDD, MVC, Domain-driven design, Agile/XP, RSpec, Jasmine

Soft Skills

Communication, Attention To Detail, Problem Solving, Adaptability, Teamwork

Socials



8

LinkedIn

live:peterstevens 510